<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Portfolio website of Jules Noël</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Portfolio website of Jules Noël</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alcohol Consumption</title>
      <link>/projects/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project2/</guid>
      <description>Where Do People Drink The Most Beer, Wine And Spirits?In this project, realized with my group at London Business School for the course “Data Analytics for Finance”, we will explore a dataset on the consumption and production of alcohol.
# Loading the datalibrary(fivethirtyeight)data(drinks)We’ll check first for any missing variable. Fortunately, our dataset is complete and we have no missing values.
# Using glimpse and skim to understand the dataframeglimpse(drinks)## Rows: 193## Columns: 5## $ country &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Afghanistan&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Albania&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Algeria&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change Anomalies</title>
      <link>/projects/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project3/</guid>
      <description>The climate change is one of the greatest challenge faced by our generation. In order to better understand its impact, it is useful to look at empirical data.The objective of this project was to explore the temperature anomalies encountered in the last dozens of years.
First, we need to download some data from the NASA.
# Loading the data setweather &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;https://data.giss.nasa.gov/gistemp/tabledata_v3/NH.Ts+dSST.csv&amp;quot;, skip = 1, na = &amp;quot;***&amp;quot;)We will now make some modifications to it and analyze it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The genius of Steven Spilberg</title>
      <link>/projects/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project4/</guid>
      <description>This project was realized in collaboration with my study group at London Business School. We exercised our R skills by looking at the relative ratings of the movis from two famous directors.
A couple weeks ago, we analyzed some data on IMBD ratings. Today, we will explore if there is a clear difference in the ratings received between Tim Burton and Steven Spielberg.
Our Null Hypothesis: The true difference in means is equal to 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 California Contributors plots</title>
      <link>/projects/project6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project6/</guid>
      <description>In this project, we learned how to reproduce the plot that shows the top ten cities in highest amounts raised in political contributions in California during the 2016 US Presidential election.
CA_contributors_2016 &amp;lt;- vroom::vroom(here::here(&amp;quot;data&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;CA_contributors_2016.csv&amp;quot;))zip_code &amp;lt;- vroom::vroom(here::here(&amp;quot;data&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;zip_code_database.csv&amp;quot;))#Assigning a numerical value to the zip code column of the databasezip_code &amp;lt;- zip_code %&amp;gt;% mutate(zip = as.numeric(zip))#Merging the two data framesCA_contributors_2016 &amp;lt;- CA_contributors_2016 %&amp;gt;% inner_join(zip_code, by = &amp;quot;zip&amp;quot;)#Cleaning the data frames in order to only have the variables we want to analyzeCA_contributors_2016_adapted &amp;lt;- CA_contributors_2016 %&amp;gt;%group_by(cand_nm,primary_city) %&amp;gt;% summarise(total_amt = sum(contb_receipt_amt)) %&amp;gt;% select(candidate = cand_nm, city = primary_city, money_raised = total_amt)# Plotting Hillary Clinton&amp;#39;s top 10 contribution citiesclinton &amp;lt;- CA_contributors_2016_adapted %&amp;gt;%filter(candidate == &amp;quot;Clinton, Hillary Rodham&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%top_n(10, wt = money_raised) %&amp;gt;% ggplot(aes(x = money_raised, y = reorder(city, money_raised))) + geom_col(fill = &amp;quot;blue&amp;quot;) + facet_grid(.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Biography</title>
      <link>/projects/biography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/biography/</guid>
      <description>Until nowMy name is Jules, I am 21 years old from Belgium and here is my biography.
From my birth to my seventeenth birthday, I lived in Belgium and enjoyed the simple things in life, tried a few sports such as Basketball, fencing on a competing level, or even rowing - at least, I tried, and fell in the water more times than I actually rowed. However, I stuck with scouts since my fifth birthday and later became a chief, then head chief at seventeen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Future Watch List</title>
      <link>/projects/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project1/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays I don’t really have the time to watch movies. My courses at London Business School are taking most of my time and the rest of my days are dedicated to my applications to Investment Banks for a summer analyst position.
So I thought, why not already compile a list of movies to watch once the exams are behind me and my internship found.
In order to construct such list, I am going to explore the data movies used during our first assignment in Data Analytics in Finance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Resume</title>
      <link>/projects/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/cv/</guid>
      <description>In case of interest, you can download my CV below my projects on the Home page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My trip in Australia</title>
      <link>/projects/australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/australia/</guid>
      <description>During the third year of my Bachelor at Maastricht University, I had the opportunity to study abroad for a semester in Australia.After long reflections, I decided to follow my courses at the University of New South Wales in Sydney.
My travel starts on the 13th July with my first long haul trip. Directly after my arrival, at night, I will go to Coogee Beach.
This, is Coogee Beach, the beach ten minutes walk away from my apartment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returns of financial stocks</title>
      <link>/projects/project5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project5/</guid>
      <description>This project, realized in collaboration with my study group at London Business Schoo, explores the returns of some stocks, we will also have the opportunity to construct our own portfolio and plot it.
As usual, we will look first at our dataset to understand it better and ensure there is no missing or duplicated values.
#Loading the data and getting its Summarynyse &amp;lt;- read_csv(here::here(&amp;quot;data&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;nyse.csv&amp;quot;))skim(nyse)(#tab:load_nyse_data)Data summaryNamenyseNumber of rows508Number of columns6_______________________Column type frequency:character6________________________Group variablesNoneVariable type: character</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
